humana.com 2014-06-27

# Internet Privacy Statement - Humana

## TRUSTe

Humana is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This Internet Privacy Statement applies only to information on Humana.com.

TRUSTe is an independent organization whose mission is to advance privacy and trust in the Networked world. As this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices monitored for compliance by TRUSTe.

By displaying the TRUSTe mark, this web site has agreed to notify you of:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours or third-party personal identification is collected from you through the website
  * The organization collecting the information
  * How the information is used
  * With whom the information may be shared
  * What choices are available to you for collection, use, and distribution of the information
  * The kind of security procedures in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under Humana's control
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information

If you have questions or concerns about this Internet Privacy Statement and/or the privacy practices of this website, you should first contact the Humana Privacy Office, PO Box 1438, Louisville, KY 40202.

If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry, or your inquiry is not addressed satisfactorily, you should then [contact TRUSTe](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with this website to resolve your concerns.

## Commitment to Confidentiality

Confidentiality is a top priority at Humana. We are committed to maintaining the highest level of confidentiality with all of the information we receive from this website's users. This Internet Privacy Statement assures you that the information you share with Humana is kept confidential and fully secure.

Links to other websites may be available to provide you with additional useful information and services. Links that take you off this website are clearly labeled. Humana is not responsible for the privacy policies or actions of those who control other websites. We encourage you to look for and review the privacy policies of any website you visit.

We may also partner with third parties to provide links to third-party websites to offer you additional information and services. You may see both the Humana logo and the third party's logo on these third-party websites. Users of these websites should be aware of who is collecting personal information and who's Internet Privacy Statement applies before providing personal information. Humana may not have control over third-party partners' use of your information.

## Collection and Use of Personal Information

Users of this website have the option to provide certain personal information. This personal information may be required in order to receive specific services. By providing such information, you are agreeing that Humana may store, process, and review such information. And we may use this personal information for the purpose for which it was collected. 

We may collect certain personally identifiable information from our users at different places within this website. Our definition of personally identifiable information includes any information that may be used to specifically identify or contact you, such as your name, mail address, telephone number, cellular phone number, text message number, fax number, e-mail address, etc. Certain information may not be personally identifiable when standing alone (e.g., your age), but may become so when combined with other information (e.g., your age and address). 

Individuals (Members), Providers, Employers, Business Partners, and Agents & Brokers have the ability to register for access to the secured area of this website. To access the secured area, you may need to provide additional information such as name, address, group number, and tax identification number. The purpose of the registration process is to verify and validate who is requesting access to the secured area of the website. Registration also enables us to tailor the information you receive. 

We may use the voluntarily provided contact information to notify website users of updates to existing products and services, new products and services, or upcoming events. Website users who do not wish to receive such notifications via e-mail or SMS (text) can choose to opt-out of receiving such information. It is our policy that e-mail and SMS (text) messages will contain an "unsubscribe" and "STOP" function, along with instructions on how to execute the opt-out function.

Some website users may have the ability to opt-out of receiving e-mail and SMS (text) messages by updating their communications preferences within the secured area of the website. 

After completing the log in process, website users have the option to change their password, e-mail address and security question and response. If the website user forgets or misplaces their password, Humana will use the security question and response to identify the website user and grant access to the website. To change personally identifiable information, registered members must contact the appropriate Humana Customer Care representative listed on the Contact Humana section of this website.

We recognize that when website users choose to provide personal information, they trust that we will protect their privacy and will provide them with choices about how that information is to be shared. Humana will not sell, trade, rent or disclose the personal information that you provide unless you authorize us to do so or required to do so by law.

There are instances in which Humana may disclose website user's personal information to our agents, third-party partners, affiliates, and subsidiaries to enable them to perform functions on our behalf. These companies are only permitted to share, store and/or use personal information for contracted business purposes.

We may share your personal information when we believe that such action is necessary to: 1) fulfill an enforceable government request; 2) conform with the requirements of the law or legal process; 3) protect or defend our legal rights or property, this website, or other users; or 4) protect your health and safety or the health and safety of this website's users or the general public.

## Technology use on this website

Information about you and your use of this website is collected through the use of session and persistent cookies. Session cookies are small text files that are stored within your computer’s memory. These files are used to facilitate your navigation throughout this website.

Persistent cookies are small computer files that are transferred to your computer's hard drive. These stored files are used in the generation of data that is fed to a contracted third party for website usage analysis. Reports created using this information will provide Humana with a better understanding of the use of this website. You may choose one of three different levels of data collection associated with the use of the first-party persistent cookie. Transfer to Persistent Cookie Opt-out Option

Humana may work with third party service providers who may place third party persistent cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies on your computer as a visitor to our website to collect anonymous information about the use of our websites. This information allows these third party service providers to customize our content and advertising. We do not permit these companies to collect any personal information about you using these technologies. 

If you do not want these service providers to collect your information, please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative (NAI)](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) website to "opt-out" of the behavioral advertising delivered by the NAI organization's member companies. [Click here ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/)to execute the opt-out process. 

Opting out from these services will have no effect on your use of this website in any way. Information stored within both session and persistent cookies are not tied to your Personally Identifiable Information.

If you are concerned about the storage and use of cookies, you may be able to direct your Internet browser to notify you and seek approval whenever a cookie is being sent to your hard drive. You may also delete a cookie manually from your hard drive through your Internet browser or other programs. You can also set your browser to refuse all cookies. Please note, however, that some parts of this website may not function properly or be available to you if you refuse to accept a cookie or choose to disable the acceptance of cookies.

This website does not respond to web browser "do not track" signals.

To gauge the effectiveness of this website, we may collect non-personal information about our website users. This information may include, among other things, your: IP address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), domain names, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We may use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the website, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically collected data to personal information.

Our mobile application may collect additional information such as Device type, Device OS version, Device name, API method, etc. We may use this information to administer the application and to analyze application trends. Geo-location data includes zip code entered by the user for use within the Provider/Pharmacy search function.

## Internal security procedures

Information that you share on the website is kept strictly confidential and fully secure. Your encrypted (encoded) information is protected using "Secure Socket Layers (SSL)" as it passes between your browser and this website. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Only authorized persons are permitted to access your personal information. All authorized persons must abide by security, privacy, and confidentiality agreements.

## E-mail

If you send questions or comments to an e-mail address listed within this website or via a contact form located within this website, we will share your correspondence with an associate most capable of addressing your questions and concerns. We will retain your communications until we have done our very best to provide you with a complete and satisfactory response. Ultimately, we will either discard your communication or, in some cases, archive it. We will not keep your e-mail address for secondary purposes. All information and correspondence you share with us will be handled in the strictest confidence.

We may agree that e-mail has become a standard communication tool used by many different parties. Unfortunately by design standard Internet e-mail is not secure. For that reason, please do not use unsecured e-mail to communicate information to us that you may consider to be confidential. Secured messaging may be available within the secured area of this website. Once you successfully log in, you may be able to use this feature to communicate confidential or private information to Humana.

## California privacy law

Residents of the State of California, under certain provisions of the California Civil Code, have the right to request from companies conducting business in California a list of all third-parties to which the company has disclosed certain personally identifiable information as defined under California law during the preceding year for third-party direct marketing purposes. You are limited to one request per calendar year. In your request, please attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. You may request the information in writing by contacting the Humana Privacy Office, PO Box 1438, Louisville, KY 40202. 

## Children's privacy

This website is not intended for use by children under the age of 18.

## Internet Privacy Statement changes

This Internet Privacy Statement is effective as of July 2000 and was last updated in April 2014. This Internet Privacy Statement is not intended to and does not create any contractual or other legal rights with or on behalf of any party.

If we decide to change this website's privacy practices, we will post those changes to this Internet Privacy Statement, the home page, and other places that we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information is being collected, how the information is being used, and under what circumstances, if any, the information may be disclosed. Humana reserves the right to modify this Internet Privacy Statement at any time, so please review it frequently.

## More information

This website is maintained by Humana, 500 West Main Street, Louisville, KY 40202
